

LANGUAGES

English – intermediate Russian – fluent Ukrainian – fluent

SKILLS

Integrated Development Environments:

NetBeans, PhpStorm

Relational DataBase Management Systems:

MySQL, PDO

Programming methodologies:

OOP, MVC

Programming Languages:

SQL PHP

JavaScript

PHP Frameworks:

Laravel Symfony

EUGENE YAVGEL

Work experience with Laravel during last 4 years, Symfony – 1 year. Strong knowledge of OOP principals, know how to use the design patterns and keep the code to PSR standards. Experience with Composer, GIT, REST API, PHPUnit. DevOps skills: Docker, docker-compose, Nginx, setup Linux (Nginx, MySQL etc.). Knowledge of HTML5, CSS3. Good understanding of JavaScript logic, writing simple scripts using jQuery.

Phone: +38 063 956 87 70

Email: eugene.yavgel@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/eugene-yavgel

EXPERIENCE

May 2021 - Present

Alliance Solutions - Laravel Backend developer

Laravel Framework, php 7.4, Mysql, GitLab, REST API, WebSockets, Redis.

September 2018 - April 2021

SmartSite - Laravel Backend developer

Laravel Framework, php 7.4, Mysql, GitLab, REST API.

January 2017 - July 2018

ZaraffaSoft - Symfony Backend developer

Symfony Framework (2.8->3.4 -> 4), php 7.1, Mysql, TDD, BDD, GitHub.

EDUCATION

April 2016 - August 2016

PHP Academy

Web-mastering on PHP.

October 2015 - December 2015

IT-Academy "STEP"

Computer courses "Passo": Web-mastering: PHP, MySQL (certificate DK-19712/15-01).

2002 - 2007

Odessa I.I. Mechnikov National University

Faculty of Economics, specialty: manager-economist, manager of foreign trade.

PROJECTS

E-commerce

This project is an e-commerce platform with a Laravel API and Nuxt front-end. The products with flexible variations, proper price implementation, a full checkout experience with dynamic shipping and payment implementations (including saved payment methods) and loads more.

See the code for back-end

See the code for front-end

Code snippets website

This project is a code snippets website with Nuxt, Laravel and Tailwind. It allows users to create 'snippets' with the steps that act as a place to store useful bits of information.

See the code

Online book store catalog

This project is a realization of the book catalog for an online store which is based on OOP by using PHP. For the development of the product catalog was used MVC programming pattern. The helper classes for working with the database and with pagination were implemented. The connection of external libraries to the script were implemented, also, formed human-friendly URLs and basic error handling mechanism were created.

See the code

DVD catalog application

This project is a building of the DVD catalog application with PHP framework CakePHP. In this project OOP and MVC were used. It works as follows: user may add an image (preferably a cover image), a website URL, the Imdb website entry and a personal rating for each DVD that is entered into the application.

There is a search and filter functionality, so user may search DVD by the name or filter by format type etc. User has an opportunity to add/edit/delete DVDs in the administrative panel.

See the code

Blog

This is a realization of the blog with Symfomy4 framework. Functionality: CRUD posts and user authentication with Auth0.

See the code